Guide to the John N. Warfield papers, 1931-2009
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 4: Additional Materials Deposited After January 2007, 1931-2009; (11 boxes)
  - Seven Challenges, November 11, 2002 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Behavioral Pathologies, Their Role in Systems Thinking, 2003 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Categories for Research on Economics, February 6, 2003 (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - Notes on the Ford Product Information Management (PIMS) Workshop Held During the Period January 11-14, 1994, May 2005 (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Notes on the Ford Culture 5th Interactive Management Workshop on Analytical Powertrain Held December 9-11, 1992, May 2005 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Thought about Thought, October 29, 2005 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Referee's Comments in a Nutshell, March 11, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - Insights into the US Automobile Industry 1990-2006, Spring 2006 (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - Applications of Interactive Design Methodologies in Protracted Conflict Situations, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - JNW Review of a Systems Research and Behavioral Science Manuscript, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - The Att of Walker Percy Excerpts, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Walker Percy (Excerpt), 1983 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Evaluation of a Design for Inconceivable Event Occurrence, May 1984 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Law and the Importance of Feelings, 1989 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Walker Percy: Art and Ethics Excerpts, 1990 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Algebraic Logic from Boole to Schroder 1840-1900 [Houser, Nathan], 1992 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Notes While Reading Ketner's "Banned Paper", May 1996 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - First Draft of Paper Outline (Study of Kant), 1997 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Notes by J. N. Warfield on the Counter-Revolution of Science by Hayek, 1997 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Founders of Discursivity in the Profession: Part 1- Insights of Michel Foucault, May 16, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Index to the Foucault Reader by Rainbow, December 2000 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - The Archaeology in Belief, Nonmember 11, 2001 (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Pragmatism, Categories and Language, 1961 (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - The Thought of C. S. Peirce (Excerpts), 1969 (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Charles S. Peirce from Pragmatism to Pragmaticism, Trans. John M. Krois, 1981 (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - Peirce's Reduction Thesis, undated (Box 95, Folder 16)
  - The Early History of Computer Design: Charles Sanders Peirce and Marquand's Logical Machine, 1984 (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - Peirce and Turing: Comparisons and Conjectures, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - Peirce and the Formal Structure of Experience, 1988 (Box 95, Folder 19)
  - Peirce-Sesquicentennial Congress, Guide to the Parallel Sessions and Other Readings, September 1989 (Box 95, Folder 20)
  - The Schroder-Peirce Correspondence; Introduced and edited by Nathan Houser, 1990-1991 (Box 95, Folder 21)
  - Peirce and the Laws of Distribution, 1991 (Box 95, Folder 22)
  - Conceptual Graphs as a Universal Knowledge Representation [Sowa, John Author], 1992 (Box 95, Folder 23)
  - Starting to Create a C. S. Peirce Dictionary, May 7, 1996 (Box 95, Folder 24)
  - Excerpts from "The Essential Peirce" and "Biographical Information", 1998 (Box 95, Folder 25)
  - Peirce as a Subject or Reference in Warfield's Writings, undated (Box 95, Folder 26)
  - Aristotle and Peirce: Two Views on Diagrams, June 17, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 27)
  - Paper for the Transactions of the C.S. Peirce Society, December 3, 2000 (Box 95, Folder 28)
  - Ketner and Cook-Charles Sanders Peirce Excerpts, undated (Box 95, Folder 29)
  - Modulacion Estructural de Sistemas, April 13, 2000 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Disenoy Practica de Sistemas, October 29, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - The Systems, Man and Cybernetics Society: The Beginnings, October 2006 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Managing the Unmanageable: Powerpoint Slide Collection Updated September 10, 2007 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - John N. Warfield Writings and Related Research Materials: DVD 1 of 2-Notes on Papers and Reports, 2008 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - John N. Warfield Writings and Related Research Materials: DVD 2 of 2-Papers and Reports, 2008 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Archie Bahm with Peirce References [Correspondence], May 30, 1983 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - With Thomas A. Cowan [Correspondence], June 15, 1998 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - With Walker Percy [Correspondence], May 1989 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Hilda Blanco [Correspondence], July 17, 1989 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - With Professor Thelma Z. Levine [Correspondence], October 3, 1989 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - George Mason Administration Officials and Others. Susan Swope, Kingsley Haynes, Fred Rossini, also Scott Staley at Ford Motor Company and Ben Broome [Correspondence], 1993 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Methodology for Categorization, in Email from Ben to Roy Smith Edited by John N. Warfield [Correspondence], November 8, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Letter From Heinz von Foester [Correspondence], September 9, 1997 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - George J. Friedman Explaining his Work with Northrup Corporation [Correspondence], July 27, 21999 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Reply to Don Stweard's Email on DSM History [Correspondence], August 21, 2000 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Letter From John R. Payne [Correspondence], December 28, 2000 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Alan G. Merton and Judith Jobbitt Thanking Warfield for Donation to GMU [Correspondence], April 2001 (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - With Paul Koda re Formal Agreement Document for SC and A Acceptance of Warfield Collection [Correspondence], May 17, 2001 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence re an Introduction to Systems Science with Editors, Publishers and Colleagues. Part A [Correspondence], 2005 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence re an Introduction to Systems Science with Editors, Publishers and Colleagues. Part B [Correspondence], 2005 (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Letter to Thomas L. Friedman, Newspaper Columnist [Correspondence], May 3, 2005 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - With Stuart Umpleby on Ideas for a Doctoral Dissertation [Correspondence], November 1, 2005 (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Status of Books Sent Gratis from Warfield [Correspondence], 2006 (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Letter to Rosalind Reid, Book Reviewer [Correspondence], May 1, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Letter to United States National Science Foundation in Support of a Proposal by George J. Friedman [Correspondence], May 6, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Letter to Carl K. Kohrt, President of Battelle Memorial Institute [Correspondence], May 28, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - With INC Magazine [Correspondence], June 2006 (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - Letter to Cal Thomas, Syndicated Columnist[Correspondence], June 2006 (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Comments on "Systems Research and Behavioral Science" A Wiley Journal [Correspondence], June 16, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Letter to Steve Balch, President of National Association of Scholars [Correspondence], June 21, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - Letter to James Aylor, Dean of Engineering-University of Virginia, June 22, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - Leadership Email to Scott Staley [Correspondence], August 9, 2006 (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - With Andre Gabus, RE Emilo Fontela [Correspondence], August 12, 2007 (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - History of Donation of Warfield Collection to GMU and ASU Libraries, 2000 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - History of the Beginnings of the John Warfield COllection, up to About 1970, July 19, 2000 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Warfield Donates Lifetime of Research to University. Mason Gazette 17:8, May 2001 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Understanding Complexity, May 3, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - The Campaign for George Mason University (Brochure), April 6, 2002 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - A Guide to the John N. Warfield Collection Located in Special Collections and Archives. Fenwick Library, George Mason University Compiled by Rose Warfield, May 2002 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of Warfield's Book From Kluwer Publishers [Correspondence], May 18, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Book Review: Understanding Complexity: Thought and Behavior by John N. Warfield, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Activity Report, 2003, A Fax Message to Kingley P. Hayes, December 22, 2003 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Book Review: An Introduction to Systems Science by John N. Warfield, February 26, 2006 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Reference List, April 30, 2006 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Strategies, July 1, 2006 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Where to Buy Warfield's Book, July 11, 2007 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Vita, September 2007 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - Sullivan, MO. Boy, 5 Has Mentality Double his Age, January 23, 1931 (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Warfield Quotes Overheard by Rose, undated (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - A Challenge for Systems Engineers: To Evolve Toward System Science (Part 1 of 2), undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - A Challenge for Systems Engineers: To Evolve Toward System Science (Part 2 of 2), undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Seven Challenges for System Designers, undated (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Creating an Interactive Systems Science Program in Higher Education, undated (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - John N.Warfield Writings and Related Research Materials: Notes on Papers & Reports (DVD 1 of 2), undated (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - John N Warfield Writings and Related Materials: Papers & Reports (DVD 2 of 2), undated (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - John N Warfield Papers for SC&A, January, 2009 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - DVD Copies of VHS, undated (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Ben Broome's Zipdisk Containing his Publicaitons and Drawings about IM, undated (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: John Warfield Papers Linked to Biblwin Databases, February 7, 2001 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: John Warfield Writings (A partial collection), 2000 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Books, Papers, Inventories, Transparencies, Presentations, 1999-2000 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Books, Papers, Inventories, Transparencies, Presentations, Pre-1999 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Warfield Writings Group 2, 1999-2000 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Digitized Versions of A Science of Generic Design, December 28, 2000 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Memo to Paul Koda, With Edited copy of Verso Page for John N. Warfield Collection, undated (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous electronic storage: Synergistic Solutions Ver. # 4.34 June 19 '98. Expires April 30 '99, undated (Box 101, Folder 8)